so let's say we have this code where
again r1 is compared to zero any branch
here if it's equal to zero if it's not
equal to zero we do this and branch out
if it is equal to zero we do this and
continue we have seen that this code
results in four instructions worth of
execution when we have the conditional
moves two instructions that actually do
the work of adye's and two instructions
that conditionally write results back to
r2 and r3 with full predication Allah
the Itanium we get the condition check
is done using the predicate set
instruction that compares equals zero on
r1 and sets p1 and p2 accordingly the
predicates are always set opposite of
each other so that if r1 is 0 P 1 is set
to true and P 2 to false if r1 is not
equal to 0 then P 1 is set to false and
P 2 is set to true now we can simply do
the add I of 1 plus R 2 into R 2 but we
will predicate it with p2 so that it
only gets done if r1 was not equal to 0
and then this instruction becomes
exactly what it was here except that now
it's predicated so that it only gets
done if R 1 is equal to 0 so as you can
see with this after we do this initial
instruction that simply sets the
predicate any code that was here simply
gets predicated with one of the
conditions the opposite condition
predicates the other branches code and
that means that first of all we can use
the same registers that we use before we
don't need the additional r4 and r5 that
we had in the previous example and
second we still do have the work of both
paths but there is no additional work to
now move the results into the registers
that have the destination registers so
the overhead here is kind of similar to
what we had with branches with branches
we needed to have the branch and then
the code from either path here we have
the condition set followed by the code
from both parts so the only really
overhead that we have in terms of
executing more instructions comes from
doing the work of both paths instead of
just one but there are no additional
instructions to select between the
results